Nneka Wooten

Community Pharmacist - ShopRite Pharmacy

Mount Laurel, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Nneka-Wooten/f5200e65b585678a

New Jersey licensed PharmD with almost 10 years of experience in hospital, retail, mail order and compounding pharmacy with extensive knowledge of Pharmacy regulations, drug-utilization review, automated drug distribution systems, and a wide range of drug delivery systems. Looking to contribute to a pharmacy team who serves the needs of a diverse patient population; while gradually increasing my clinical role.

Willing to relocate to: Delaware - Maryland - Pennsylvania

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Community Pharmacist

ShopRite Pharmacy - Medford, NJ - February 2013 to Present

Accept and dispense prescription medications

- Provide consultation on prescription and non-prescription medications for storage, dosage, side effects, and drug interactions
- Provide advice on selection of Over-The-Counter medications to treat common illnesses such as flu, cold sores, or headaches
- Educate patients on proper handling of medical devices such as blood pressure monitor and glucose meters
- Monitor patient medication compliance and over-usage patterns
- Supervise pharmacy staff members including pharmacy technicians, pharmacy clerks, etc.
- Proper management of patient records and pharmacy files
- Maintain appropriate inventory on pharmaceutical and medical supplies
- Identify patient's drug-related problems and effectively communicate with physicians and other healthcare practitioners
- Work in conjunction with physicians, nurses, other pharmacists, pharmacy interns, etc.
- Provide specialized educational programs and health promotions to help patients manage chronic health conditions such as hypertension and diabetes
- Prepare preparation of liquid medicines, ointments, powders, tablets and injectable.
- Administer vaccines based on need, for example: Flu vaccine during flu season.
- Provides consultation on all new and refill prescription before providing them to the patients to ensure proper understanding of the medication being dispensed.
- Communicate with HMO's and PBM's concerning billing/reimbursement, drug substitutions, and prior authorizations.

Customer Care Pharmacist

Wedgewood Pharmacy - Swedesboro, NJ - July 2010 to November 2012

Received inbound phone calls from customers and serviced their needs effectively and efficiently.

- Processed new prescriptions from Veterinarians and Physicians through multiple contact channels.
- Consulted with physicians about appropriate dosing, administration and dosage form of prescribed medications.
- Verified accuracy of prescriptions prior to preparation.
- Consulted with patients and pet owners about indication of use, dosing, and adverse effects of medication prescribed.
- Responded to customer (internal and external) requests for technical/clinical information.

- Provided oversight to customer service personnel to assure operational compliance with pharmacy regulations and standard operating procedures.
- Quickly understood and analyzed customer needs to solve and document customer problems in accordance with state and federal pharmacy regulations and company SOPs.
- Documented and followed up on any quality event incident.
- Created and verified calculations for new product preparations.
- · Exposure to Regulatory documents.

Hospital Pharmacist

Kennedy Memorial Hospital - Cherry Hill, NJ - June 2007 to December 2010

Entered and reviewed prescriptions for correct dosing.

- Ensured accurate dispensing of medications to inpatients and outpatients.
- Consulted with physicians to confirm details of prescriptions.
- Handled inquires in reference to dosage, indication, compatibility and drug availability.
- Prepared and supervised the preparation of suspensions, ointments, capsules, liquids, TPN's and IV fluids.
- Monitored pre-packaging and labeling of unit-dosed medications for patients.
- · Recorded and Maintained inventory of pharmaceuticals.

Compounding Pharmacist

Wedgewood Pharmacy - Swedesboro, NJ - December 2008 to July 2010

Provided supervision and guidance in the execution of compounding various prescription medications for example: gels, capsules, suspensions, ointments, soft chews etc. in a GMP batch manufacturing environment.

- Ensured all raw materials were properly weighed and staged prior to compounding each preparation.
- Maintained GMP's in the Compounding and Pre-Weigh areas.
- Maintained a sterile and safe work environment.
- Ensured validated compounding procedures were followed.
- Adherence to SOP's and procedures on cleaning, sterilizing, weighing and compounding.
- Reviewed equipment cleaning and sterilizing log books to ensure accuracy and completeness.
- Reviewed, edited, and created SOP's as needed.
- Assisted with the editing and improvement of new and existing formulations.
- Provided direction, training and follow-up training for all compounding employees.
- Monitored equipment for necessary maintenance, improvements, or upgrades.
- Provided quality checks for pre-weighed chemicals and finished preparations.
- Supervised technicians throughout the process of compounding preparations.
- Verifying the final preparations for appropriate appearance, consistency, and quantity.

Mail Order Pharmacist

Medco Health Solutions - Willingboro, NJ - January 2008 to December 2008

Interpreted, entered and verified prescription information into a computerized drug-distribution system.

- Consulted and assisted physicians with converting certain brand medications to their generic equivalent when it was better economically for the patient without compromising care.
- Performed drug utilization review of medications to ensure that there was no drug-drug, drug-disease, or drug-allergy interactions.
- Achieved daily production goals while maintaining a high level of service and without compromising quality of care
- Easily and quickly shifted between duties/functions when asked by management in order to meet business needs.
- Performed scheduled audits of automated processes to assure medication accuracy.
- Counseled patients on directions for use and possible side effects of medication(s).

Hospital Pharmacist

Our Lady of Lourdes Hospital - Camden, NJ - February 2007 to January 2008

Inputted patient's prescriptions into computerized drug-distribution systems.

- Consulted with physicians and nurses to ensure that patients received accurate dosage of medication and appropriate dosage form, for example: tablet, injection, ointment, inhaler, etc.
- Consulted with medical professionals about possible side effects and drug interactions associated with medication.
- Prepared and performed quality checks of sterile medications for example intravenous medications, IV chemotherapy drugs, ophthalmic preparations, and etc
- Monitored the pre-packing and labeling of unit dose medications.
- Supervised the preparation and production of various medication dosage forms, for example: ointments, powders, tablets, capsules, and liquids.
- Checked accuracy of physician calculations of TPN's for tube feed patients.
- Ensured the appropriate storage of medicines to maintain freshness and potency.
- Procured and maintained inventory of medication and supplies used in the pharmacy.

Pharmacist-In-Charge

CVS Pharmacy - Camden, NJ - December 2005 to February 2007

Recruited, managed, and trained pharmacy technicians.

- Inputted and dispensed prescriptions using a computerized drug-distribution system.
- Consulted with physicians to ensure accurate dispensing of medication, minimize or eliminate drug interactions, disease state management and reduce the risk potential side effects of prescription and/or OTC medications.
- Maintained accurate and up to date patient information in pharmacy database.
- Interacted with HMO's and PBM's concerning billing, drug substitutions, and prior authorizations.
- Responsible for Pharmacy Human Resources such as interviewing pharmacy staff; providing performance reviews; coaching and counseling with pharmacy technicians.
- Maintained accurate and preset inventory levels by following defined ordering practices from store warehouse and approved outside vendors.
- Complied with outlined loss prevention procedures including securing C-II safe and arming pharmacy alarm at closing.
- Participated in production meetings and provided recommendations for improvement in workflow.
- Ensured Policy and Procedures were in compliance with the board of pharmacy.

Retail Pharmacist/ Pharmacy Intern

Walgreens - Pennsauken, NJ - May 2005 to December 2005

Interpreted, processed and filled prescriptions for customers daily.

- Performed order entry and dispensing of prescriptions from pharmacy database.
- Maintained accurate patient records, dosing information and directions for use of prescribed medications.
- Counselled customers about various disease states, symptoms of illnesses and side effects of medications.
- Consulted with medical professionals (physicians, nurse practitioners, etc.) with regards to medication dosage, drug interactions, disease state management, and potential side effects of prescription and/or OTC medications.
- Maintained accurate inventory of prescription and OTC medications.
- Interacted with HMO's and PBM's concerning medication coverage and prior authorizations.

EDUCATION

PharmD

University of the Sciences in Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA 2000 to 2005

Pre-Pharmacy Rutgers University-Camden Campus - Camden, NJ 1997 to 2000

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

- Extensive knowledge of Pharmacy regulations, drug-utilization review, automated drug distribution systems, and a wide range of drug delivery systems.
- Easily adapts to change and a fast learner.
- Work well under pressure while staying organized and managing time well.
- Both team oriented and ability to work independently.
- Honest and Dependable with Outstanding Interpersonal skills.